We quickly discuss about the incident response process for our discovery tactics.
Let me give an example.
You are a threat analyst and during your investigation, you found there's something where
happening like one of the user. Let's think about one of the threat hacker executed an
advanced IP scanner inside the machine. So at that point, what actions you'll be going to take
for this process? So the initial thing, you need to stop the threat attacker. So they just
pull it straight, advance IP scanner for scanning the environment. And you need to do something
before they start the scanning. They start scanning in the environment.
So not only that, maybe they can jump on to the other departments too. I mean, you compromised
HR department. And you put an advanced IP scanner in the HR department machine.
And that's HR domain. And the next domain you are targeting will be in
programming software development department. And you compromised and you are trying to
compromise another domain. And you did, you moved to the software development department. And you
installed an advanced IP scanner in the machine. You are trying to install advanced IP scanner
in the machine. So the reason, the thing we can perform for an incident response for the discovery
tactics, you can block the hash of advanced IP scanner in the EDR tool. So which you will be using
so that that will be a perfect thing. You can, you can, you can do it, do it there. Okay.
Let me show you something. So how to get the hash of the executable
it can use PowerShell to get the hash. But in EDR, you can easily find out the hash of an
executable. So it's really, really simple one. So the command we are using get file hash.
And we need to be a path here, you know, to mention the path, see slash users, user downloads.
And let's say, advanced IP scanner. And you need to mention the algorithm. So most of the
EDRs will be supporting a chart to five six to five six. So now you can see the hash of,
hash of the executable here, 26 D five seven. So this is the way you can take the hash of
the executable and you can block in the firewall or you can block in the security
defense tool. So whatever you are using, maybe it's so false, defender,
or cloud stakes, and you don't own our extra, anything. Okay. So you can get the hash and you can
block the hash and then you don't. So other than that, you can see, send the credentials for the
user, user, user executed. So in our scenario, he, if the user, net user, user, active.
So you can, you can, you can, I don't think the command was correct or not, but you can disable
the user temporarily. So if something is going on and reset the crunches of the user. So that will
be what's going to find. So let's hop off from this section and we'll continue our, uh,
attack scenario in the next section. See you guys. Goodbye.